It's time for Enjoy Simple English
森崎ウィンです
毎週木曜日は2019年度に放送した
Wisdom from the Westをお送りします
古典が語る西洋の知恵と題しまして
人生の知恵や教訓までさりげなく教えてくれる
イソップ偶話を集めました
今回はThe Father, The Son and The Donkey
父親と息子とロバです
では早速聞いてみましょう
One day, a father and his son were going to the market with their donkey.
The father held the donkey with a rope, and his son walked beside it.
They walked like this for a while.
Then, they met a traveler.
The traveler laughed at the father and son.
He said,
You are fools! Why are you walking your donkey?
You should ride it.
The father thought for a while.
He decided to do as the traveler said.
He put his son on the donkey's back and started walking again.
Soon, they passed a group of travelers.
One of the men said in a loud voice,
Look at that! The son is riding the donkey, not the father!
He is not a good son.
Younger people should walk and let older people ride.
He is such a lazy son.
I feel sorry for the father."
The father thought again.
He decided to do as the man said.
So the father told his son to get off the donkey and the father got on.
They passed two women.
The women started to talk with each other.
One of the women said out loud,
Did you see that?
The father is riding the donkey, not the son.
The father is not a good parent.
I feel sorry for the son.
The father didn't know what was right.
He thought long and hard.
そこで、彼らは考えたことがあった。
彼らは両方、動物の上に立ち上がった。
彼らは少し歩いて行った。
そして、今、彼らは市場に近づいていた。
多くの人が、彼らに指を振りかけ始めた。
父は止まった。
そして、一人の人に質問した。
失礼します。
何かが間違っているのですか?
まあ、悪い動物のために申し訳ありません。
彼はあなたとあなたの息子を 少しずつ背負っているのです
また父は正しいことを 知らなかったのです
みんな彼に 異なることを言っていたのです
彼は考えたり考えたり 新しい計画をしていたのです
これが正しいことだと 考えていたのです
彼らは木製の穴を見つけ
動物の足を巻いて 動物の足を巻いていたのです
ダンキーは木製のステッカーから 横に座っていました
父と息子は ステッカーを持って
市場へ歩きました
みんな笑っていました
市場への道を通ると
ダンキーの一つの足が 折れてしまいました
ダンキーは足を踏んで
ステッカーが落ちて 水の中に落ちてしまいました
ダンキーの足がつながったから 水に死んでしまった
大人は全てを見つけた
彼は言った
この教えは良いものだと思う
誰もが幸せになるなら 誰もが幸せにならない
今日も素敵な教訓得られましたね
いや本当ね僕この物語の中で好きな文があるんですけれども
If you try to make everyone happy, no one is happy
もうみんなを満足させようとするともう誰も満足しないよってことですよね
しっかり自分の意見を持つことの大切さ学べましたね
それではまた明日お会いしましょう
See you tomorrow